# JEREMY BARBER

Web developer (1+ year) with a background in IT (2 years), sales (2 years) and intelligence operations (3.5 years). Experienced in designing and developing user interfaces, RESTful APIs, databases, and responsive websites. Proven ability to convert requirements into software and improve workflow.



# CONTACT

- jeremydev2020@gmail.com
- **\** 702-569-2155
- Las Vegas, Nevada
- unlimitedcode.dev
- O @onlytruejeremy
- in Jeremy Barber

## **SKILLS**

# **Programming**

#### Front End:

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, ReactJS, JSON, Formik, Yup

#### Middle Tier:

NodeJS, ExpressJS, Joi, JWT, BCRYPT, CORS, Helmet

## **Back End:**

SQL, MongoDB, FireBase

#### IT

#### **Networking**

Configure, support and maintain network infrastructure

#### Cybersecurity

Risk management, Threat analysis and prevention, Identity and access management

## Soft Skills

#### **Customer Relations**

Communication, CRM Tools, Relationship Building, Sales

# **Analysis**

Research, Critical Thinking, Problem Solving

# **EDUCATION**

- # Security+, CompTIA 2018
- GEOINT Professional Certification, NGA 2018
- Intelligence Operations, Cochise College 2016

# **WORK HISTORY**

Dec 2020 - CurrentV NET, Las Vegas

#### IT Technician

- Improved quality of service and reduced client attrition by researching, diagnosing, troubleshooting, identifying and implementing solutions to software, networking and hardware issues customers were experiencing involving fixed wireless.
- Converted dozens of residents into customers increasing yearly revenue by over \$25,000 within two months.
- Resolved account related issues for clientele ensuring they were able to manage invoices and file trouble tickets through their customer portal accounts.
- Developed informational documentation enabling faster resolution of common problems when assisting customers.

**12/2020 12/2020** 

**♀** WebMall, Las Angeles

# **Full Stack Developer**

- Designed and eveloped RESTful services for invoice, discount and order features of the application.
- Built new ReactJS components for customer, vendor and admin-facing pages with role guards ensuring only appropriate access was granted.
- Enhanced security of features using form validation and data validation in ReactJS and NodeJS respectively, preventing SQL injection attacks.
- Worked alongside other developers in an agile environment to resolve bugs and implement new features preventing system-breaking code from entering the repository.
- Increased user experience by implementing Flexbox and media queries that ensured mobile responsiveness.
- Utilized git for version control enabling rollbacks in the event erroneous code disrupted performance of the application.

max Jan 2020 - May 2020

**♀** American Income

#### **Benefits Advisor**

- Performed outbound calls, met with prospects and converted dozens of residents into clients.
- Increased customer retention by outreaching to previous clientele and reenrolling them into benefit programs.
- Maintained logs of interactions with leads and customers in proprietary CRM.

Mar 2016 - Dec 2019

**Q** U.S. Army.

#### **GEOINT Analyst**

- Identified and resolved networking, hardware and software problems in RHEL7, Windows and antenna/radio devices.
- Briefed dozens of high level personnel from military departments, government agencies, and defense contracting companies on intelligence related matters.
- Produced a quantitative and qualitative assessment for a pilot program under the Joint Artificial Intelligence Center (JAIC), used by key decision makers to improve the functionality of AI.
- Created templates using formulas in excel that optomized workflow and reduced analyst burden.
- Produced a continuity book for incoming analysts reducing on-boarding and training time.